我们要去圣巴巴拉拿摇篮车
So we're going to Santa Barbara to pick up the bassinet.
或者我们省下5个小时
Or we can save five hours
直接去拐角处的婴儿市场
and go around the corner to baby town.
你今天要干嘛
What are you doing all day?
-杰 -没关系的 妈妈
- Jay! - It's fine, mom.
怎么没关系 今天是曼尼的生日
No, it's not fine. Today's Manny's birthday.
呀 孩子 真是抱歉
Aw, jeez. I'm sorry, kid.
别担心 罗本一家要带我去吃生日午餐
Don't worry. Reuben's family's taking me for a birthday lunch.
你看 连罗本一家都记得
You see? Even the Reubens remembered.
我们会在6点回来
We'll be back at 6:00,
然后带你去吃特别生日晚餐 好不好
and we're taking you to a special birthday dinner. Okay?
-真要吗 -杰
- We are? - Jay!
抱歉 孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
我并不抱歉 那只是障眼法
I wasn't sorry. It was a setup.
我们要给他办一个大型惊喜生日派对
We're throwing him a big surprise birthday party.
他竟然完全信了 那个小兔崽子
And he totally fell for it, the little jerk.
那正是惊喜派对的意义所在嘛
I mean, that's the whole point of a surprise party.
你把自己真心爱的一个人
You take someone who you really love
当傻子一样耍
and you play 'em like a fool.
那才不是我们这样做的全部意义
That's not the whole point of all this.
曼尼感觉自己有点受冷落
Manny has been feeling a little bit neglected,
所以我想给他一个最特别的日子
and I wanted to give him the most special day.
我们三个人单独庆生
This is the last birthday
也就这最后一次了
that it's only going to be the three of us.
我迫不及待想看到小宝贝了
I can't wait to see the little dope's face.
然后那个自以为是的卡萝·曲就开始咆哮
...And then that smug Carol Chu was all,
"没有环境影响报告是不能挖的"
"You can't dig without an environment impact study."
然后我"嘭"地一下
And then I was like, "Bam!"
把报告甩在了查理的桌子上
and then I slapped the study onto Charlie's desk,
卡萝就在那里 "但 但 但是"
and Carol was like, "But--but--but--"
然后我就说 "去"你妈的
and then I was like, "Chu on that!"
你那么说了吗
You said that?
没用嘴说 用我的眼神和潇洒的转体
Well, not with my mouth. With my eyes and my swivel.
你呢 今天工作怎样
So how was your day at work?
就那样 还行
Oh, you know, fine.
是吗
Yeah?
我真是个笨蛋
I'm an idiot.
我知道小卡自从回去教书就一直很挣扎
I know Cam's been struggling since he went back to teaching.
那些学生 那些教员
The students, the faculty--
没一个好对付的
None of it's clicking.
他绝不会想听到
The last thing he needed
我最近工作有多成功
was me going on about my latest work triumph.
之后情况更糟糕了
And then it got worse.
二爸 快过来 我们的婚礼要开始了
Come on, daddy. It's time for our wedding.
-什么情况 -莉莉和我要结婚了
- What's happening? - Oh, Lily and I are gettin' married.
什么情况
Uh, what's happening?
当她求婚的时候 我觉得有些诡异
When she proposed, I thought it was a little weird,
但后来我查到有些女孩会经历这个阶段
but then I read it's a phase that some girls go through.
-所以 -是 我只是觉得这超可爱
- So... - Oh, no, well, I just think it's the cutest thing ever.
给你 二爸 我为你做了这枚戒指
Here, dad. I made you this ring.
太太太太太可爱了
Cute, cute, cute, cute, cute, cute, cute!
你有戒指要给我吗
Do you have a ring for me?
莉莉 没有戒指就不是婚礼了
Well, Lily, it wouldn't be a wedding without a ring.
耶 好有爱啊
Yay. Loving this!
大爸 走开
Daddy, move.
好吧 我猜我要坐在新郎那边
Okay, I guess I'll just go sit on the groom's side.
得了 小卡 好玩而已
Oh, come on, Cam. It's fun.
好玩 真是超好玩啊
Oh, it's fun. It's--it's super fun!
你终于结婚了 万岁
You finally got married! Hooray!
-嗷 -你还好吧 宝贝儿
- Oh! - Are you okay, sweetie?
你觉得呢
What do you think?!
真是百年难见的奇景啊
This is very rare indeed.
奇葩书呆子回归自然本性
Geekus nerdipithicus in its natural habitat.
-一如既往地独自一人 -我的摄像机
- Alone as usual. - Mine.
嘿 拿回来
Hey, give it back.
歌洛莉亚叫我给曼尼的生日会录像 妈
Gloria asked me to record Manny's birthday. Mom!
艾丽克斯 还给你弟
Alex, give it back To your brot--
算了 我实在懒得管
Mm, sorry. I tried to care.
这是我上周在时装店赚的所有钱了
This is everything I made at the boutique last week.
你全拿去 我就什么都没了
I'm not gonna have any money left for me.
你在被学校开除之前就该想到这点
Should've thought of that before you got thrown out of school.
你住在这里 就得交租
You live here, you pay rent.
你以前可是个老好人
You used to be fun.
以前 是吗 上大学的时候
You used to be--what? Oh, yeah, at college.
等等
Uh, hang on. Wait.
歌洛莉亚说今晚6点要给曼尼一个惊喜
Gloria says that we are surprising Manny 6:00 tonight,
但她要我们4点就到那
but she wants us there at 4:00,
就是说她要我们来布场
which means she's expecting us to do the setup.
我说我们5点走
I say we leave here around 5:00.
好的
Great.
是我同事肯尼
That's Kenny from work.
我去开
Oh, I'll get it.
我们要去集市
We're going to a street fair,
所以我们派对上见
so we'll just meet you guys at the party.
你和这个新同事肯尼
Oh. You've been spending a lot of time
-最近老是黏在一起嘛 -打住
- with this Kenny from work. - Stop it right now.
有开始暧昧吗
Is it gettin' romantic?
-没-- -是的吧
- N-- - Yeah...
-其实嘛... -是的吧
- Well... - Yeah.
妈 这是肯尼 爸 你们已经见过了
Mom, this is Kenny. And, dad, you already met.
是哦 首先 肯尼 胡须真浓密啊
Uh, yeah. First of all, Kenny, sick ponytail.
谢谢
Oh, thanks, man.
-肯尼给我们店设计牛仔裤 -呵呵
- Kenny designs jeans for our boutique. - Uh-huh.
提醒我了 给你带了东西
Oh! That reminds me. I got something for you.
你穿多大的 32-34吗
What are you, a 32-34?
你"多大" 36 38岁吗
What are you, 36, 38?
-你是我肚子里的蛔虫吗 -穿上看看
- What are you, in my mind? - Put 'em on your body.
好的 好的
Will do. Will do.
菲尔 亲爱的
Phil, honey, d--uh--
肯尼可是个名人哦
Kenny is kind of a big deal.
那个时尚网站叫你什么来着
What does that fashion web site call you again?
"牛才" 拼写和"牛仔"很像
a "Jean-ius." Spelled like "Jeans."
真是愧不敢当
Mortifying.
还有"衣架巨星"
And a "Rack star." Ohh.
那个标题是什么来着
Hey, what was the headline again?
对 "他是天命牛仔奇才"
Oh, yeah. "He's denim-ite."
那你这周多尴尬呀
What an embarrassing week you've been having.
是呀
Ooh. Yeah. Mm.
我只是想保持鲜活的创造力
I'm just trying to stay fresh creatively, you know,
把我的精髓融入男士服装里
made my bones in men's apparel,
现在我正和当地的这些精品店合作
and now I'm working with these local boutiques...
尝试涉猎女款牛仔
just trying to get into girls' jeans.
-菲尔 -菲尔已经不在了
- Phil! - There's no Phil here!
这牛仔裤太合身了
These jeans just slipped on me so perfectly.
我已经改名为"牛仔灰姑娘"
My name must be pantsarella.
赞 舒服吧
Boom! Comfortable, right?
舒服得像尿布一样
Like a diaper. Mm.
-我们该走了 -是呀
- Well, we should get going. - Oh, yeah.
但是...你想说点什么
Um, but you wanted to say... Something.
-对 是的 是的 抱歉 -说
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sorry. Yeah. - Okay.
听着
Uh, listen...
你弄得好像是给我们夫妻都送了牛仔裤
You made it seem like you had jeans for both of us,
但是克莱尔没有拿到她的 所以...
And Claire hasn't gotten hers yet, so...
-真是不好意思 -别担心
- I am so sorry. - Don't worry about it.
给
Here you go.
-要喜欢哦 -肯尼 你太赞了
- Enjoy. - Kenny, you're amazing.
-不是 -玩得开心
- No, man. - Have fun.
你才是真的赞
You're amazing.
我真喜欢他
I love him.
菲尔
Phil!
-你觉得他喜欢我吗 -菲尔
- You think he likes me? - Phil!
那是个约会 他们要去约会
That is a date. They're going on a date.
什么 他几乎跟我同岁了
What? He's practically my age.
是的 对 对 对得很
Okay. Uh, yeah, right, right.
什么样的中年男人会对一个
And what middle-aged guy would be interested
年轻 漂亮 刚成年的女人感兴趣呢
in a young, attractive, newly legal woman?
对了 所有中年男人都那样
Oh, that's right! All of them.
不对 我就是个例外
That's not true. I wouldn't.
真的吗
Really?
赫敏·格兰杰不是吗
Hermione Granger?
-什么 -嗯哼
- What? - Mm-hmm.
我只是个"哈利波特"迷而已
I'm just a "Harry Potter" Fan.
是啊
Yeah.
她有长大成为一名可爱的年轻女士吗
Has she blossomed into a lovely young lady?
是的 但是 卢克
Yes, but--Luke,
我再也不告诉你任何秘密了
I'm never telling you anything!
天啊 杰 快看 多漂亮啊
oh, my god, Jay! Look how beautiful!
你看看这多挤 书店却空荡荡的
Look at this. But the bookstore is empty.
正因此中国才要领先我们了
That's why China's kicking our ass.
不是吧 59号
Ay, no. 59.
我们来太晚了 而且我们还得去取饮料
We're so late, and we still have to pick up the drinks.
借过 不好意思 借过
Excuse me. I'm terribly sorry. Excuse me.
先生 那正是我订的蛋糕
Sir? This is my cake right here.
我直接付钱 然后拿蛋糕走人怎么样
How about I'll just leave money, I take it?
先生 我要是答应你
Sir, if I did for you,
就得答应所有人的要求
I'd have to do it for everyone.
你就当我是个特例好啦
Not if you just did it for me.
不好意思 不好意思
Excuse me. Excuse me.
我们有急事 我们要举办生日派对
We're in a hurry. We have a birthday party.
你怎么不早说呢
Oh, why didn't you say something?
急着开生日派对的顾客真是"少见"呢
We don't see many of those around here.
你以为我会被你恶劣的态度唬住吗
You think you can intimidate me with that attitude?
-你以为我多大 -34[胸围]
- What do I look like to you? - 34!
谢谢 但重点是我儿子在等着...
Thank you, but the point is that my son is waiting in--
歌洛莉亚 跟他争不值得
Gloria, it's not worth it.
我们不用求这些人
We don't need these people.
-我们 -走吧 能找到更好的蛋糕
- Jay, we need... - Come on. We'll get a better cake.
你疯了吗 我们怎么可能...
Are you crazy? How are we gonna...
我有办法 打扰一下 女士
I've got it covered. Excuse me, miss?
抱歉我刚才在里面那么大声嚷
I'm sorry I raised my voice in there,
尤其是还当着小宝宝
especially in front of the baby.
我知道他们是多么的敏感
I know how delicate they can be.
你这么说真是太贴心了
Oh, you're so nice to say that,
但他们其实比你想象中坚强
but you know they're sturdier than you think.
实际上 每一天我都学到一些小...
In fact, every day I learn these little mir--
行了 你保重
Yeah, take care now.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, honey.
二爸 包包里装的什么
Daddy, what's in the bag?
是给曼尼买的生日礼物
Oh, it's a present for Manny,
我还给你大爸买了小礼物
and I also got your other daddy a little something
因为他今天心情不太好
'cause he's been feeling down today.
你的眼睛怎么样了 宝贝
How's your eye, sweetie?
没事了 只是小伤而已
Oh, it's fine. It's just a scratch.
我们这边走 亲爱的
Let's go this way, honey.
小卡 你要穿西服去曼尼的生日派
Oh, Cam, are you wearing a suit to Manny's birthd--
好 来摘掉你的绷带
Okay, let's get your hospital band off.
我喜欢这绷带
I like it.
-就当作"蓝色物品"吧 -小卡
- Okay, that can be your "Something blue" then. - Cam?
大爸 我想开我的新车
Daddy, I wanna drive my car.
什么新车 哇塞 新车
A car? Oh. A car.
马上就好 亲爱的
Just a second, sweetie.
谁有理由不让这两位新人成婚
Okay, does anyone know a reason why these two shouldn't be wed?
她是我老婆
She's my wife.
那么以糖果帝国授予我的权利...
Okay, so by the power vested in me by the State of Candy Land...
犹他州授予的吧
And Utah.
我宣布你们正式结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
大爸 我可以去玩我的新车了吗
Daddy, I wanna play with my car now.
当然可以 去吧 宝贝
Okay. Of course. Yes, sweetie.
但记着 我们要顺着迎宾队列徐徐走过
But remember, we have to walk down the receiving line.
噢 真是漂亮的出场
Oh! What a turnout.
小卡 你居然给她买了辆车
Cam, y-you got her a car?
我无法忍受你娶她竟然舍不得花钱
I can't help it that you skimped on your wedding.
听着 我知道这一切背后的原因是什么
Okay, look, I-I know what's underneath all this, all right?
现在你的生活中
Right now in your life,
-你感到非常... -错
- you're feeling, you know, very... - No.
请不要把我和女儿结婚说得那么丑陋
Please do not turn me marrying my daughter into something ugly.
莉莉只是在经历一个人生阶段...
Lily is having the time of her--
小卡
Cam!
拜托 那不是我的错
Oh, please. Do not blame me.
你我都早有预料 她很可能
We always knew there was a strong possibility
会是个糟糕的司机
she'd be a terrible driver.
克莱尔 我知道我们晚了
I know we're running late, Claire.
我们马上就到
We'll be there soon.
你们先开始布置吧
Just start setting up.
你说"真是个意外"是什么意思
What do you mean, "Surprise, surprise"?
等等 我得挂了 你先忙着吧
Hang on. I've gotta go. You take care.
-怎么了 -杰 我找不到停车票了
- What's the matter? - Jay, I can't find the parking ticket.
别着急 一切都会好起来的
Calm down. Everything's gonna be fine.
太好了 是个男服务生
Oh, good. It's a male attendant.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
想想我不在的话 你会怎么给自己解围
How would you get out of this situation if I wasn't here?
你好哥们
Hey, pal,
我家保姆找不到停车票了
My housekeeper forgot her ticket.
你们得倒回去 然后到三层的
You're going to need to back up, go up to the third level,
付款台去付停车费
and find the pay station.
你就不能放我们过去吗
Ay, you can't just let us go?
我肯定是放在哪儿了 但就是找不到
I know I put it somewhere here but I cannot find it now.
去付款台 在三层
Pay station. Third level.
你先放我们走嘛
Maybe you can let us go now,
下次人家一次性给你"两次"好吗
and then next time I do you two times?
你们想出去 唯一的办法就是
The only way you're going to get out
回到付款台交费
is to go back to the pay station.
实际上 还有一个办法
Actually, there is another way.
你还好吗
You okay?
好极了 我们再去撞几个栏
Let's drive through something else!
盛大的庆典马上就要开始了
The gala celebration is only minutes away.
到处是美味的饮品
Delectable refreshments,
兴奋的小同学们
excited classmates,
这是什么 世上最美的景象不过如此
And what's this? The most beautiful sight of all?
走开
Go away!
他一把年纪 她年轻貌美 真恶心
He's old. She's young. It's gross.
亲爱的 他们没什么的
Honey, nothing's happening.
年轻人总是喜欢向长辈学习
Young people seek out older mentors all the time.
当年我17岁时
When I was 17,
我和我朋友斯黛西的妈妈走得很近
I was really close with my friend Stacy's mom.
罗宾逊女士以前也是拉拉队员
Mrs. Robinson was a former cheerleader,
她特别清楚训练后该如何给我按摩大腿
so she knew just how to massage my legs after practice.
她有一种自制的缓解肌肉酸痛的药膏
She had her own homemade Bengay that didn't burn
无论怎么在身上蹭都不会有灼热感
no matter where she rubbed it on me.
如果我有机会去她那里
If I had the chance to go over there,
我不会错过任何机会的
I never missed an opportunity.
我想你错过了很多"鸡会"
I think maybe you did.
我把礼物忘在车里了
Oh, I forgot the present in the car.
好吧 你去取 我去放个"水"
Oh. All right. I'm gonna go take a squirt while you grab it.
-好笑吧 -好爱我们俩
- I know! - I love us!
太有才了
It's crazy!
-我要揍死他 -菲尔
- I'm gonna fight him. - Phil.
别拦我 克莱尔 我要狠狠揍他一顿
No, Claire, I'm gonna fight him up real nice.
要不还是先威胁他一下吧
How about you start with a threat?
克莱尔 你能帮我一把吗
Hey, Claire, um, could you help me with this?
行行行
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
你到那边去
Yeah, you gotta go around the other side.
-我得盯着点菲尔 -怎么了
- I need to keep my eyes on Phil. - Ooh, what's happening?
他马上要去把海莉的新男友吓跑
He's about to drop the hammer on Haley's new boyfriend.
他比她大一倍 太令人作呕了
He's twice her age, and it's disgusting.
是啊 让我想起
Yeah, reminds me of
你当年约会过的某奶酪工厂的小经理
a certain manager at the Cheesecake Factory that you dated.
你说陶德啊
Oh. Todd.
他可是有车又有权
He had a camaro... and power.
他糟透了 你跟他约会就是为了气老爸
Ugh! He was nasty. You just did it to get a rise out of dad.
是啊 但事与愿违
Yeah, well, look how well that worked out.
老爸一点反应都没有 而我却落了个
It didn't bother dad at all, and then I was stuck with a guy
身上一股土豆皮味
who smelled like potato skins
且用"倘若"这种蹩脚词的男友
and said "Supposably".
你必须承认 老爸那招还挺灵的
Well, you have to admit, dad played that pretty brilliantly.
没过几周
You know, after a few weeks,
你就厌倦了那男人 把他给甩了
you got bored with him, and then you dumped him.
是啊
I did.
我狠狠把他给甩了
I dumped him up real nice.
-菲尔 -克莱尔 拜托
- Phil. - Claire. Oh, come on.
菲尔 千万别对肯尼说任何话
Phil, you can't say anything to Kenny.
-什么 -不行
- What? - No.
我知道海莉为什么这样做
I know why Haley is doing this.
她是为了报复你对她那么严厉
She's doing it to get back at you for being so hard on her.
我当初也是这么对付我爸的
I did the same thing to my dad.
首先 我跟你爸可不一样
First of all, I'm not your dad.
而且你觉得我会任由她跟他约会吗
And do you think I'm just gonna let this happen?
相信我 你越是生气
Trust me. The more it bothers you,
他呆的时间就越长
the longer he stays.
而我们越是坐视不管...
The more we ignore it...
来击个掌 老爹
Up top, dad!
好耶
Yeah!
搞定
Nailed it.
那位威利·尼尔森就会越早走人
...the sooner Willie Nelson's on the road again.
我好纠结
I'm so conflicted.
我脑子里知道你说得有道理
What you're saying makes sense up here,
我心里却不能接受
but it's not what I wanna do here.
我臀部这里却感觉好舒服
And I just feel so damn comfortable down here.
忘了告诉你 我把那东西放在"后背箱"里了
I forgot to tell ya I put that in the trunk.
知道 我不得不伸到你的裤子下面去拿
Oh, I know. I had to reach under your jeans.
-难以置信啊 -我们太有才了
- I can't believe that! - We're so crazy!
你个小可爱
It's adorable!
出去转转吧
Wanna see outside?
好啊
yeah.
宝贝 我给你买了饼干
Sweetie, I brought you a cookie.
我在急诊室吃过了
I ate at the emergency room.
你那眼罩贴合得很完美啊
You worked that in seamlessly.
别这样 那只是场意外
Oh, come on. It was-- it was an accident.
别再自责了 走 我们也一起乐去
Stop beating yourself up. Hey, let's go mingle.
不 其实吧
No. You know what?
我有几个学生在这 我现在...
Some of my students are here, and I'm just--
-我没那个心情 -好吧
-I'm not in the mood. -All right.
小卡 我们得谈谈了 我知道你在闹什么别扭
Cam, we're gonna talk about this. I know what's going on.
你肯定在学校工作不顺
You're obviously going through something at school.
你心里挣扎难受 我还火上浇油
You're struggling, and I have just made things worse
夸自己工作如何得心应手 没考虑你的感受
By bragging about what a hero I've been at work recently.
但这不是在跟你竞争
And it--it's-- it's not a competition.
我的成功就是你的成功
You know, my victories are your victories.
你的失败就是我的失败
Your defeats are my defeats.
塔克老师 他在这儿
Hey, Mr. Tucker! There he is!
*拉动琴弦*
*Bow across a cello string*
*弹奏钢琴*
*Piano keys a hammerin*
*和声齐唱*
*Voices raised in harmony*
*致我们亲爱的卡梅隆*
*For our dear ol' Cameron*
爱你 塔克先生 你是最棒的
We love you, Mr. Tucker! We love you! You're the best!
再见老师
Bye! Bye!
是啊 确实像噩梦一般
Yeah, it's been a nightmare.
谢谢你认为我不能应付自己的工作
And thank you for assuming I'm terrible at my job.
不是的
No.
我们到了 抱歉迟到了
Hey, everybody. Sorry we're late.
我们路上遇到点事耽搁了
We got caught doing a bunch of stuff.
或者什么事儿都不干
Or not doing a bunch of stuff.
好啦 曼尼马上就到了
Okay, manny is going to be here soon,
我们把步骤再过一遍
So let's go over the plan.
听到他快进来时 我们把灯关掉
When we hear him coming, we turn off the light.
他一进来 我们就把灯打开
Then when he comes in and turns it on,
然后大喊"惊喜"
We all scream "Surprise!"
有笔吗 我得记下来
You got a pen? I wanna write this down.
他正从车道走过来
He's coming up the driveway!
他来早了 大家各就各位
He's here early! Hurry up!
快 快
Hurry! Hurry!
嘘 嘘 嘘
Ahh, shh, shh, shh.
快点 别让邻居看到
Quick. I don't want the neighbors to see us.
你确定屋里没人吧
You're sure we're alone?
确定 他们6点才会回来
Yeah. They're not home till 6:00.
太好了 因为我要给你个特别的生日礼物
Good, 'cause I wanted to give you your birthday present.
其实 我想看清你的脸
Actually, I'd like to see your face.
灯太晃眼了 我知道
It's harsh, I know.
之前跟他们说过该装个调光器
I begged them to put in a dimmer.
不是的
No!
惊喜哦
Surprise.
曼尼 对不起 我们本无意...
Manny, we're so sorry. We didn't mean to--
无意什么 把我人生中最美好的时刻搞砸吗
What? Ruin the greatest moment of my life?!
真是谢你了 妈
Thanks again, mom!
本应接受惊喜的人成为了惊喜制造者
And the surprised becomes the surpriser.
这派对真是太精彩了
This party had everything.
曼尼
Manny
曼尼 出来吧
Manny, please come out.
如果你不是来往门上装送食槽
Unless you're here to cut a food slot on my door,
那么你可以走了
You can leave now.
没人想捉弄你
Nobody's going to make fun of you.
对孩子来说 剪个新发型就会被同龄人取笑
Kids make fun of you if you get a haircut.
我制造了性丑闻 这下他们有的吐槽了
I just gave them a full-blown sex scandal.
大家本想开心地为你庆祝的
Everybody's so excited to celebrate with you.
哎呀 不会吧
Ay, no.
婴儿急着要出来 可我还不能让他出来
The baby was ready, but I was not.
让曼尼和别人分享他的母亲已经够委屈他了
It was bad enough that manny had to share his mother.
还要和别人分享生日 那可不行
I couldn't let him share a birthday, too.
你给我乖乖待在里面
You stay in there!
你不是劝我出来吗
I thought you wanted me to come out.
是啊 是啊 出来吧
I do! I do! Come out!
我们还给你偷了个漂亮的蛋糕
We stole you a beautiful birthday cake.
歌洛莉亚 闪开 让我来
Gloria, tag out. Let me give it a shot.
你来劝劝吧
Yes, you fix it.
我不会粉饰这件事 那确实挺难堪的
Look, I'm not gonna sugarcoat this, kid. That was rough.
走开
Go away!
但这事也有好的一面
But there's an upside.
毕竟吻女孩最让人高兴的
The best thing about kissing a girl
莫过于可以向朋友炫耀
Is you get to tell your friends.
但问题是没人会相信你
The problem is, they never believe you.
现在你有一大帮证人了
But you had witnesses.
刚才那事可以拿来吐槽好几年呢
We're gonna be talking about this one for years to come,aren't we?
那可不 肯尼
You said it, Kenny.
曼尼看起来像个小大人儿
Manny seems to me like a-- like a real old soul.
肯尼非常擅长观察人的心理年龄
Kenny is amazing at telling the age of a soul.
谢谢 宝贝儿
Thanks, babe.
年龄其实取决于心态 不是吗
Age is nothin' but a state of mind, you know?
比起他 我更像个14岁男孩呢
I mean, I'm probably more of a 14-year-old than he is.
相信我 我深知14岁孩子什么样
Believe me, I know 14-year-olds.
他有个14岁的女儿
He has a 14-year-old daughter.
-是的 -太酷了
- Oh, yeah. - Oh, cool!
亲爱的 用不着你来动手 园丁会修剪的
Oh, honey! You don't have to do that. They have a gardener.
相信我对此事的判断
Trust me on this.
我是想相信你
I want to,
但多年来你的判断几乎从来没对过
But you're just so wrong about so many things.
继续练习
Just keep practicing.
小卡 抱歉之前侮辱到你了
Hey, cam, I-I'm so sorry that I insulted you earlier.
我以为你工作上遇到了什么不顺
I thought that there was something going on at work,
但显然我错了
And, obviously, I was wrong.
那么你又错了 确实跟工作有关
Well, you're wrong again. It is about work.
真是把我闹糊涂了
This is a fun game.
我之前没说是因为觉得很难堪
I didn't bring it up before because I was embarrassed.
昨天真的是我工作最顺利的一天
But yesterday was the best day I've had at work yet.
我和同学们老师们打成一片
I clicked with the students, the teachers.
-我终于融入进去了 -我懂
- I finally felt like I belonged. - I get it.
你怎么会懂 我话还没说完呢
You couldn't possibly get it. I'm in the middle of my story.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
每天下午2:30 我都会给莉莉打电话
Every day at 2:30, I call Lily,
然后一起泡饼干吃
And we dunk a cookie together.
可是昨天
And yesterday,
我忘记了
I forgot.
把女儿忘在一边
Forgot my own daughter.
显然 她为此记恨着我
And obviously, she resents me for it.
所以她让你跟她结婚 以此报复我
It's why she asked you to marry her, to get back at me.
好吧 我必须指出她才5岁
Okay, here I-I need to point out that she's 5
也不是《豪门恩怨》中的角色
And not a character from "Dynasty."
我越是想亲近她
And as much as I try to connect with her,
越是弄巧成拙
I just keep making it worse.
或许是你太刻意了
Maybe you're just trying too hard.
大家快进来
Everybody, come in!
曼尼要下来了
Manny's coming down.
谁把毛巾捡起来 免得到时有人绊倒
Somebody pick up that towel before someone trips.
好 我来
Okay. I got it.
大爸
Daddy!
别怕 大爸来救你 我是怎么回事
Okay! Daddy's coming! What's wrong with me?!
好了 各位 那么
Okay, everybody. So,
我们先唱歌 然后送礼物 最后吃蛋糕
We sing, then presents, then cake.
那是哥伦比亚的传统
That's a colombian tradition.
谁都别提刚才的事
And we do not speak of what happened before.
就当没发生过
Nobody saw anything.
那也是哥伦比亚的传统
That's another colombian tradition.
他来啦 我们的小寿星
Here he is, the man of the hour!
生日...
Happy...
歌洛莉亚 你没事吧
Gloria, you okay?
不 我没事 我没事
No, I'm fine! I'm fine.
"生"...
Hap--aah! Aah!
不会吧 她尿了
No way! She peed!
是羊水破了
Her water broke!
目前为止我的14岁过得不堪入目
So far, 14's not my favorite age.
我没事 继续唱 继续唱
No, it's nothing! Keep singing! Keep singing!
生...我不行了
Ha... Ay! Stop it!
我们去趟医院
We're gonna pop on over to the hospital.
比萨的外卖就快到了
Pizza's on the way.
你们能把地板擦擦吗
You think about it, run a mop over this area?
曼尼 对不起 原谅我
Ay, manny! I'm so sorry, okay?
生日录像改为自然纪录片
And the birthday video becomes a nature film.
卢克 别闹了
Luke, come on.
天啊 要生了
Oh my gosh! It's happening!
曼尼 今天真的很抱歉
Manny, I am so sorry about today.
本想让你过个快乐的生日的
I just wanted you to have a happy birthday.
说到生日
And speaking of birth-- days...
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
我不会在午夜前生下这个孩子的
I'm not letting this baby out before midnight.
今天是属于你的
This is your day.
我不会让你每年与人分享的 好吗
I'm not gonna let you share it every year, okay?
妈 听我说
Mom, look.
没错 我最近有一些被冷落的感觉
Yeah, I've felt a little neglected lately,
但我已经一个人独占你的爱14年了
but I've had you to myself for 14 years.
你这话让我有些难过
That makes me a little sad.
拜托 如果我们真的忘记了他的生日
Oh, please. If we had actually forgotten his birthday,
他现在就会亲着一个美丽的褐发小姑娘
he'd be out right now kissing a cute brunette.
那是好事
Things work out.
你知道无论怎样我都会爱你吗
You know that I love you no matter what?
你为了照顾我的情绪 而尝试将另一个人
You're trying to hold another person inside of you
留在肚子里 你的爱我明白
to spare my feelings. Message received.
握得好用力
Ooh, that's a strong grip.
好了 好了
Ah, that's a--that's a-- that's a--
快生了
Ah, she's gettin' close.
她的宫口现在已经扩张到美丽的8厘米
She's at, like, 8 beautiful centimeters.
嘿 我们不认识吧 我叫肯尼
Hey. I don't think we've met. I'm Kenny.
你好 我叫"被恶心到"
Hi. I'm disgusted.
米奇尔 她甚至都不想看我
Mitchell, she won't even look at me.
她现在谁都看不见
Well, she can't really look at anyone.
瞧谁回来了
Oh! Look who's back...
又回来了 这次怎么了
Again. What happened this time?
他把我扔到了泳池里
He threw me in the pool.
不 不是这样的
No, that's not what happened.
就是这样的
It kind of is.
卢克 得了 我们不用再经历一次
Luke, come on. We don't need to relive it.
-大爸 -看这个
- Daddy! - Oh, look at this.
-我来了 大爸来了 我是怎么回事 -米奇尔
- I'm coming! Daddy's coming! What's wrong with me?! - Mitchell.
她掉进泳池时 是叫大爸救命
When she fell in the pool, she screamed for daddy.
她叫你二爸 叫我大爸
She calls you "Dad." She calls me "Daddy."
-她害怕时叫的是我 -瞧
- She got scared, and she called out for me. - See?
我想大爸是多虑了
I guess daddy was worrying about nothing.
但是 有时我是会犯傻的
But, you know, I can be silly sometimes.
-你总是犯傻 -不 你才傻
- You're always silly. - No, you're silly.
不 你总是犯傻
No, you're always silly.
我的天 我是怎么回事啊
Oh, my god. What's wrong with me?
宫缩越来越密集了
The contractions are coming a little bit closer.
我想应该叫护士了
I think we have to call for a nurse.
不 杰 不要 对不起
No, no, Jay! No, please! I'm sorry.
为什么
For what?
我还不知道
I don't know yet,
但我知道宝宝会让母亲抓狂
but I know that babies make mothers crazy.
我会犯错
and I'm going to be making mistakes,
然后我会怪你
and the I'm going to be blaming you.
求你别离开我
Please don't leave me.
你现在有点情绪化了
You're a little emotional right now.
但我好久没照顾宝宝了
But it's been so long for me,
对你来说更是时过百年了
and a hundred years for you.
我们依然会是优秀的父母吗
Are we still going to be good at this?
这将是一次历险
It's gonna be an adventure,
但这是我们最拿手的
but that's what you and I do best.
看看今天
Look at today.
我觉得我们从未如此开心过
I can't ever remember having more fun with you.
我好幸运
I'm so lucky.
快出来
Now get out.
-我以为你想要我... -不是说你
- But I thought you wanted me to-- - No, not you.
快出来
Get out!
我们走吧
Hey. Let's go.
好的
Oh, right.
爸 妈
Hey, guys?
肯尼和我想去一家餐厅
So Kenny and I were thinking about going to this restaurant.
可以啊 我没意见 你呢菲尔
Oh, sure. I don't have a problem with that. Do you, Phil?
没有
No.
事实上 认识肯尼
In fact, it has been such a pleasure
非常开心 我们请客
getting to know Kenny, it's our treat.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
没有
No!
把信用卡给他们 菲尔
Give them your credit card,Phil.
而且那家餐厅相当远
Also, uh, this restaurant is pretty far away,
所以我们可能会待到很晚
So we might be out late.
亲爱的 你只会年轻一次
Well, sweetheart, you are only young once.
可能住酒店更好吧
Oh, might even make sense to just stay in a hotel.
好的 都刷我们的卡
Okay. Put it on the plastic!
太好了
Great!
好啦 明天见
Okay. See you tomorrow!
再见
Bye-bye.
是我前妻
It's my ex-wife--
不是好的那个
Not the good one.
你想怎样
What do you want?!
胆小鬼游戏玩得真好 克莱尔 她走了
Nice game of chicken, Claire. She's gone!
她会回来的 我几乎可以肯定
She is coming back. I am almost positive.
几乎
Almost?!
为什么我要听你的 为什么
Why do I listen to you? Why?
你说iPod是个失败的发明 是错的
You were wrong about the ipod being a failure.
你说番茄是蔬菜 也是错的
You were wrong about tomato being a vegetable.
我甚至不想提你最喜欢的"行星"冥王星
I don't even want to talk about your favorite "Planet" Pluto!
而且除非她是对《观点》里的面善女主持撒谎
And unless she was lying to the good ladies of "The view,"
人家名字是黛米 不是迪米[歌手]
It's "De-mi," Not "Dem-mi"!
你居然让我和他一起离开
You were going to let me go with him?!
那不正是你希望的吗 亲爱的
Isn't that what you wanted, honey?
你是怎么回事啊
What's the matter with you?!
我离开大学后你就一直表现很怪
You've been acting so weird ever since I left college!
说清楚下 你不是离开了大学
For the record, you didn't leave college.
你是被迫离开
You were asked to leave.
你们永远不肯让我忘记这一点 尤其是爸
Oh, which you guys never let me forget, especially dad.
亲爱的 你父亲...
Honey, your father--
你不用告诉我他的想法
Oh, you don't have to tell me what he thinks, okay?
我令他非常失望
I'm a huge disappointment to him.
我每天都能从他的表情中看出这点
I see it on his face every day.
他表现的根本不想让我出现在他身边
He acts as if he doesn't even want me around.
给我停车票
Give me the ticket for the car.
-菲尔 -我去追她
- Phil-- - I'm going after her!
这个胆小鬼游戏也许对你爸有用
This little chicken game may work for you dad,
但对我没用 那是我的宝贝女儿
but it doesn't work for me. That's my little girl.
我要让她知道
I need her to know
地球上没有男的能配得上她
that no guy on earth is good enough for her,
更别说是什么媚俗的中年牛仔裤销售员
let alone some slimy, middle-aged jean salesman!
什么情况
What's this?
享受这一刻吧
Just enjoy it.
人生中有着各种里程碑
There's all kinds of milestones in life,
有你期望经历的
The kind you expect to live through--
初吻
The first kiss.
生日
Birthdays...
毕业
Graduations.
如果够幸运 一两次婚礼
If you're lucky, a wedding or two.
甚至是家里增添了新成员
Or even a new addition to the family.
还有你从未梦想过
Then there's the kind
会再次经历的时刻
you never dreamed you'd get to live through again.
好可爱
So adorable!
太讨人喜欢了
So sweet!
我的天
Oh, my goodness!
看他 太完美了
Look at him. He's perfect!
看他 好可爱
Look at him. He's so cute!
那才是人生中最美妙的
And that's the best kind of all.
我为什么要向你剧透
Why am I spoiling it for you?
你会自己发现的
You'll see for yourself.
-很痛苦吗 -是
- Oh, was it difficult? - Ay, si.
那是我人生中最痛的20分钟
It was the most painful 20 minutes of my life.
瞧啊
Oh, well, look at that!
-你又苗条了 -是的
- You're skinny again. - Yeah.
是的
Yeah.
等等 他是我舅舅吗
So wait. He--he's my uncle?
不 他算你半个小舅子
No. He's your half-brother-in-law.
他是我们的舅舅
He's our uncle.
半舅舅还是全舅舅
Half-uncle or full uncle?
什么是全舅舅
What's a fuluncle?
好啦 别觉得自己应该赖着不走
Okay, so don't feel like you gotta stick around.
-我们明天见 -我们明天再来
- Okay. We'll see you tomorrow then. - Okay, we'll be back tomorrow.
-拜 舅舅 -恭喜
- Bye, uncle. - Congrats.
-再见 -他好可爱
- Bye. - He's adorable!
可爱吗
Is he?
我一点也不喜欢这小家伙
I don't like this one bit.
我们详谈
We'll talk.